Hear that?
That's nothing.
Which is what I, as a speaker at today's
conference,
have for you all.
I have nothing.
Nada.
Zip.
Zilch.
Zippo.
Nothing smart.
Nothing inspirational. Nothing even
remotely researched at all.
I have absolutely nothing to say
whatsoever.
And yet, through my manner of speaking,
I will make it seem like I do.
Like what I am saying is brilliant. And
maybe, just maybe, you will feel
like you've learned something.
Now, I'm going to get started with the
opening. I'm going to make a lot of hand
gestures. I'm going to do this with my
right hand. I'm going to do this with my
left. I'm going to adjust my glasses.
And then I'm going to ask you all a
question. By show of hands, how many of
you all have been asked a question
before?
Okay, great. I'm seeing some hands. And
again, I have nothing here.
Now, I'm going to react to that and act
like I'm telling you a personal
anecdote.
Something to break the tension.
Something to endear myself a little bit.
Something kind of
embarrassing.
And you guys are going to make an aww
sound.
It's true. It really happened.
And now I'm going to bring it to a
broader point. I'm going to reel you
back in.
I'm going to make it intellectual.
I'm going to bring it to this man right
here.
Now,
what this man did was important, I'm
sure.
But I for one have no idea who he is.
I simply Google image the word
scientist.
And now, you see, I'd like it to seem
like I'm making points, building an
argument, inspiring you to change your
life. When in reality, this is just me
buying
time. Now,
if you don't believe me, let's take a
look at the numbers. This is a real
thing that's happening right now.
The number of talks that I'm giving is
one.
Interesting facts imparted thus far in
said talk, well, that's going to be a
zero.
My height in inches is 70.5. Note the
point five there.
2 * 6 = 12, and then interestingly
enough, 6 * 2 also equals 12. That's
math.
352 is a three-digit number.
1 2 3 4 5, and then almost immediately
following that, we get 6 7 8 9 10.
Now, to add more filler here, I'm going
to give you a couple more numbers to
consider. Uh 18.
237.
5,601.
2.6 million.
Four.
24. Staggering.
These are real numbers, all of them.
And to follow that up, let's take a look
at some graphs. Now, if you take a look
at this pie chart, what you're going to
see is that the majority far exceeds the
minority.
Everybody see that?
Cool, isn't it?
And let's take a look at this bar graph,
cuz it shows similarly irrelevant data.
Now,
I'm doing this because I'd like to make
it seem like I've done my homework. If
you were, say, watching this on YouTube
with the sound off, you might think,
"Huh.
Okay.
This guy knows what he's talking about."
But I don't.
I'm floundering, panicking, I've got
nothing. I'm a total and utter phony.
But, you know what?
I was offered a TED Talk.
And damn it, I'm going to see it
through.
Now, if you take a look behind me, these
are just words paired with vaguely
thought-provoking stock photos.
I'm going to point at them like I'm
making use both of my time as well as
your time, but in reality, I don't know
what half of them mean.
And now, as these continue, I'm just
going to start saying gibberish. Waga
wawa. Gabba gabba. Turkey. Mouth in a
mouth.
Chip, trip, my dog Skip.
Rip it and dip it, Richard.
I'm an itty-bitty baby bopper and I'm
hungry in my tum-tum.
Brad Pitt, Uma Thurman.
Names, things, words, words, and more
things. And see, it feels like it might
make sense, doesn't it?
Like maybe, just maybe, I'm building to
some sort of satisfying conclusion. I
mean, I'm gesticulating as though I am.
I'm pacing, I'm growing in intensity,
I'm taking off my glasses, which by the
way, are just frames.
I wore them to look smart, even though
my vision
is perfect.
And now, I'm going to slow things down a
little bit.
I'm going to change the tone.
I'm going to make it seem like I'm
building
to a moment.
AND WHAT IF I WAS?
AMAZING, isn't it? What can you do?
Life's a roller coaster.
You know,
if there's one thing you take away from
my talk, I'd like you to think about
what you heard at the beginning.
And I'd like you to think about what you
hear now.
Because it was nothing,
and it's still nothing. Think about
that.
Or don't. That's fine.
And now I'm going to stop talking.
Thank you.